To whom it may concern,

As a new graduate from the University of Ottawa, my career counselor gave me what I consider to be some pretty bad advice: "Just get any job, and figure the rest out later." While I think I could have gained good transferable skills and on-the-job experience anywhere, I wanted to make sure my first step gave me opportunities for professional development, mentorship, and rotations through different departments. I've built my work ethic on one simple principle: Work smarter. I'm the person who looks for efficient procedures, finds ways to streamline them, and consistently strives to boost the productivity of everyone around me. It's what's earned me lead positions amongst university groups and it's what I know I can do as an entry level mechanical engineer at your company

Please find enclosed an entailment of my work quality and references in making your decision to see the choice I am. To hear from you would be great! Feel free to contact me day or night as I am currently *not* working.

Sincerely, Obinna Azike.

Obinna Gerald Azike

221 Lyon St N – Unit 1905, Ottawa ON, K1R 7X5 Telephone: (613) 276-0435 Email: azike_gerald@yahoo.ca

Employment

Internship

Fidelity Pensions - Lagos December 2017 to January 2018

Internship

Platform Insurance Brokers - Lagos April 2017 to August 2017

Education

Bachelor of Applied Science, Mechanical Engineering and Engineering Management Option

University of Ottawa, ON 2013-2018

Entry Scholarship of \$12,000

Availability: I am available immediately and willing to relocate. Status: Canadian citizen.

Member of Ontario Society of Professional Engineer

Relevant courses: Computer-Aided Design, Control Systems, Heat Transfer, Reliability and Maintainability in Engineering Design, Mechanical Vibration Analysis, Fluids Mechanics, Thermodynamics, Manufacturing, Mechanical Engineering Laboratory, Accounting, Marketing, New Business Ventures, Organization Behaviour.

Technical Skills

- Research and analytical skills developed from numerous group projects
- Wrote multiple engineering and laboratory reports and reviewed formal engineering documents, including project proposals.
- Knowledge of file management, file compression and file indexing and comfortable in the use of SolidWorks, Java, Matlab, StarCCM+, Microsoft Office/Excel.
- Knowledgeable with in use of 3D printing.

Communication Skills

- Fluent in English, with a basic working knowledge of the French langua
- Comfortable with public speaking and working in large groups.
- Able to give presentations with the use of PowerPoint and Prezi.
- Delivered weekly PowerPoint presentations and provided reports with updates about ongoing design projects to the lead engineers.

• Participated in several group projects which included preparing technical reports and oral presentations.

Applied Projects

Design of An All Terrain Vehicle (09-12/17)

- Project consisted of designing and analyzing an off-road vehicle for a Baja race that will survive the severe punishment of a rough terrain.
- This project created a parametric design system to deal specifically with heavily mudded tracks.
- I was responsible for the parametric design of the chassis suspension and the steering, and providing appropriate anchor points for the engine, the transmission, electrical components and the wheel hub.
- As a group, we were responsible for designing all components from the Briggs and Stratton 10hp OHV Intek engine shaft to drive the wheel inclusively as well as designing the brakes and front wheel assembly.
- The group designed a gear system that allows for a forward and reverse motion of the ATV.
- The use of engineering sketchbooks and Solidworks were essential for the creation of this idea.
- Matlab was also integrated to simulate the proposed design and make it parameterizable.
- This design was 3D printed for some physical tests.

Snow Blower Gear Reducer Design (01-04/16)

- Project development of a lateral offset gearbox with detailed specifications.
- Evaluated the stresses, shaft and safety factors while making proper design and engineering assumptions.
- Integrated through a computational fluid dynamics program to produce a graphical representation of related stress points in the shaft and design.

Battery Swap Station Design for E-Formula One Cars (09-12/15)

• The project consisted in designing a battery swap station that replaced the old

method used for battery swapping in formula E racing cars.

- As a team we were presented a problem and without assistance we used various problem solving techniques to design a solution.
- The machine was able to swap batteries from the bottom of the car and replace it with a fully charged battery in an autonomous operation.
- Used SolidWorks to design every aspect of the swap station while adhering to specific dimensional guidelines.

• Integrated through a Matlab computer program to simulate the proposed design and to identify suitable linkages and mechanisms to satisfy the design requirement.

Quadcopter Drone Manufacture and Design (09-12/15)

- Intensive research to ensure a unique design is created and materials are available in the market or can be sourced locally.
- Introduced a multisim electrical circuit design program to stimulate the electrical control system of the quadcopter aided by the use of a Naza-M V2 flight controller.
- Successfully modelled the quadcopter design using SolidWorks computer program.
- Reduced material cost by 40% by manually manufacturing the quadcopter landing gear using 3D printers, by personally analyzing the Arduino program code, or removing redundancies which resulted in a smaller board and microprocessor being used.